<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raj Hiray Blog</title>
    <link>https://rajhiray.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Raj Hiray Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 15:23:26 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajhiray.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get Email Alerts When COVID-19 Vaccines Become Available Near You</title>
      <link>https://rajhiray.github.io/post/covid19-vaccine-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 15:23:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rajhiray.github.io/post/covid19-vaccine-tracker/</guid>
      <description>The COVID-19 vaccination program in India was earlier available to people above 45 years of age but starting May 1st, anyone above the age of 18 years can get vaccinated. That said, vaccine availability remains an issue countrywide and it is cumbersome to manually check slots every few hours.
Vaccinate India Site: Vaccinate India  The government’s official website cowin.gov.in  has a useful search section that allows you see the nearby vaccination centers in your city or zip code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to Open Source Software</title>
      <link>https://rajhiray.github.io/post/contributing-to-open-source-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 17:33:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rajhiray.github.io/post/contributing-to-open-source-software/</guid>
      <description>Why Contribute to Open Source? Contributing to open-source projects gives you an opportunity to volunteer your time to improve a project used by you and your community. This is probably one of the coolest aspects of programming.
Why do people contribute to open source? Plenty of reasons!
 Improve a project used by you It’s empowering to be able to make changes, even small ones You can learn a lot from the source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managed Identity Implementation of Azure Key Vault</title>
      <link>https://rajhiray.github.io/post/azure-key-vault-managed-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 17:33:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rajhiray.github.io/post/azure-key-vault-managed-identity/</guid>
      <description>With any key/password store I always thought that the weak link was the credentials used to access it. If that single point of failure was compromised then all your secrets would be vulnerable. Microsoft have overcome this by creating the Managed Identity. A Managed Identity is generated by a resource within Azure and can be configured to access resources that use Azure AD for authentication.
Managed Identity Managed identities for Azure resources is a feature of the Azure Active Directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Key Vault Fundamentals</title>
      <link>https://rajhiray.github.io/post/azure-key-vault/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 17:33:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rajhiray.github.io/post/azure-key-vault/</guid>
      <description>You’ve probably heard some version of the story about a developer who mistakenly checked in his key/secrete to source code.
As developers we all understand and care about keeping dev and production secrets safe but managing those secrets on your own or especially in a team can be cumbersome.
Safeguarding Secrets In software Development Most of us know it’s a best practice to keep secret settings like connection strings, domain passwords, or other credentials as a runtime configuration and outside the source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure global .gitignore</title>
      <link>https://rajhiray.github.io/post/configure-global-gitignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:39:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rajhiray.github.io/post/configure-global-gitignore/</guid>
      <description>How do you treat files you don’t want to include in your commit?
Write it in .gitignore, isn’t it?
How you treat files you want to ignore in every git repository? always put file name in .gitignore?
For example you are using Visual Studio 2019 IDE, VS19 will create .vs folder in your project folder. you always ignore these files in every single project you’re working on by configuring in project level or repository level .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://rajhiray.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 15:31:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rajhiray.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Vaccinate India The government’s official website cowin.gov.in  has a useful search section that allows you see the nearby vaccination centers in your city or zip code. You’ll also know how many vaccine doses are available at a specific center and the earliest date when the vaccine slots are likely to open up.
Based on the public CoWIN API  , I have developed an open-source vaccine tracker that will automatically monitor vaccine availability near your location and will send email alerts as stocks become available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public speaking</title>
      <link>https://rajhiray.github.io/public-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 15:31:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rajhiray.github.io/public-speaking/</guid>
      <description>PUBLIC SPEAKING </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://rajhiray.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 19:59:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rajhiray.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>.avatar{float: left;margin: 0 15px 15px 0;width: 30%;}.certificats{table-layout: fixed;width:100%;margin: 20px 0px;}.certificats td{vertical-align:top;}#contact{font-size: 6em;text-align: center;}I&amp;rsquo;m a passionate software developer with over 3 years of professional experience. Love to code and design algorithms, large scale distributed systems for real world problems.  I’ve been working on technologies like C#,.NET Core, REST API, Windows Services, MS SQL Server, Kusto, SSIS and ADF ETL, Power Automate, Power App, Power BI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
